Finding Aid for the Morton B. King Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Morton B. King Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0241
.42 linear_feet
Biography/History
Morton B. King received a Bachelor of Arts in English, from Vanderbilt University, in 1934, and his Masters of Arts in Sociology in 1936. While a student at Vanderbilt University he had contact with several Agrarians on the faculty and off. Since he grew up in a small Middle Tennessee town on a farm he was particularly drawn to the main Agrarian message. He was also involved with the Student Christian Movement whose theme was racial justice. As a Depression Era graduate entering the job market, he chose to become a relief worker, instead of going on relief. He later became a Professor of Sociology at the University of Mississippi.
Scope and Contents
This .21 linear feet collection of 14 file folders contains recollections, correspondence, newsletters, a newspaper, newspaper clippings, a satiric flyer, and materials related to the Student Christian Association.
- Correspondence – Robert Penn Warren to Morton King
  - [February 1956]
  - February 15, 1956
  - March 20, 1956
- Correspondence – Morton King to Robert Penn Warren
  - February 15, 1956
  - March 24, 1956
- Flyer (satiric)
  - The Vanderbilt Patriot, April 29, 1936
    [for a sports related anti-war rally on campus – against the Arkansas Razorbacks]
- Newsletters
  - The Revival of the Fittest, July 25, 1934
  - Tenn Nu-News – Fall, 1932
- Newspaper
  - Vanderbilt Hustler
    - February 17, 1933
    - April 4, 1933
- Newspaper Clippings
  - 1930-31
  - 1933
  - November 23, 1933
  - June 12, 1934
- Recollections
  - The Agrarians and Race, 1930s & 1956
    written by Morton King, February 1993
  - The Student Christian Movement – Vanderbilt, 1930-34
    written by Morton King, August 31, 1993
- Student Christian Association
  - Installation Service Program, May 13, 1934
  - Retreat At Morton King’s, September 17, 1933
  - Student-Young People’s Mass Meeting, April 2, 1933
  - Minutes of Southern Regional Council of the Student YMCA, June 16-23, 1933
  - Report of National Council of Student Christian Associations, April 6-10, 1933